Fatmir Likrama

Houston, TX +1 512 784 9641 limanoa@gmail.com https://flikrama.github.io/

Analytics and Energy professional experienced in technical consulting, data analytics, statistics, project management and software development. Strong analytical skills with a background in Physics and Engineering with proven communication skills.

Skills

- More than 8 years of experience as a consultant, technical analyst and software product manager converting technical analysis to business value.
- Expert usage of MS Excel, Visio, PowerPoint, Access, TFS and Jira.
- Proficient with Power BI and Tableau analysis, visualization, customer segmentation and forecasting studies. Familiar with geospatial technology.
- User of SQL and Python in a business and technical environment.
- Tutored Statistics with SPSS to graduate and undergraduate students for 3 years.
- Familiar with AWS and Azure cloud environments.
- Agile/Scrum practitioner.
- Proven verbal and written communication skills; fluent in Spanish, Albanian and Turkish.

Achievements

- Published on time series analysis, signal processing (wavelet transform) and automatic change point detection methodology besides several geomechanics applications in the energy industry
- Developed internal scripts for data transfer from geological databases to FEM platforms using Python and SQL
- Accomplished software product migration to cloud within 6 months as a product owner
- Pioneered Neural Network, Self-organizing Maps and Fuzzy Logic algorithm implementation in Rock Physics products

Employment Experience

Data Analyst III Texas Health and Human Services 09/2020-Present Austin, TX Data Management Team

- Performed forecasting, segmentation studies and ad hoc summaries on Texas immunization data.
- Identified and quantified Immunization Registry data exchange errors.
- Tested, developed and presented standard operating procedures for accurate and complete data streaming for bi-directional data streaming new system.

Rock Physics Product Owner Landmark Software, Halliburton

6/2019 - 5/2020

Houston, TX

- Managed a rock physics products software portfolio within an Agile framework.
- Maintained relationships with clients for requirements and input.
- Facilitated collaboration between different functions and aligned all teams involved with development and release.

Consultant/Analyst Halliburton Consulting

5/2012 - 6/2019

Houston, TX

- Performed Geomechanics Consulting/Analytics work for oil and gas operators all around the globe.
- Enhanced offerings' portfolio by adding 4D Geomechanical modeling and wellbore stability workflows considering shale swelling chemical effects.
- Translated technical content into actionable business items for management review and decision making.

Self Employed Tutor Self Employed

1/2009 - 5/2012

Austin, TX

Tutored undergraduate and graduate students in person and online on Statistics (using SPSS), Math, Physics and Chemistry.

Engineering Intern Schlumberger

5/2007 - 9/2007

Sugar Land, TX

Modeled mud filtrate invasion, fluid flow to a sampling probe and drilling mud filtrate clean up in a Wireline Formation Testing utilizing Eclipse 300 Reservoir modelling software.

Research Assistant University of Texas at Austin

6/2006-12/2008

Austin, TX

Collaborated in research led by Dr Jon Olson and Prof Mukul Sharma on coupled fluid dynamics and mechanics of weakly cemented and un-cemented formations, permeability variation, stress and fracture reorientation and wellbore failure analysis modeling.

Education

University of Texas at Austin, Master of Science in Engineering, PE

8/2006 - 12/2008

Austin, TX

Thesis: Study of Mechanical and Flow Properties of Weakly Cemented and Un-cemented Sands Using Discrete Element Method Modeling.

Bogazici University, Bachelor of Science, Physics

9/1999 - 6/2003

Istanbul, Turkey

Graduated ranking top of 2003 class, Physics Department.

US Citizen since 2015